

SABBIR AHMED

Web Developer

3

+(880) 152 146 3599 sabbir5795@gmail.com



www.mrsabbir.website



Basabo, Dhaka- 1214

PROFILE

Web developer with 3+ years of experience in design and developing user interfaces, testing, debugging staff within ecommerce and web applications technologies. My experience developing ecommerce and web applications is primarily PHP Framework, but I am also comfortable using PHP (Laravel & WordPress) and JavaScript framework (VueJs). I have proven ability in optimizing web functionalities that improve data retrieval and workflow efficiencies in ways that save time and improve user experience.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2019 B.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering

Daffodil International University | Dhaka

- GPA 2.95
- Favorite area of study: Embedded System.

2012 - 2014 Higher Secondary School Certificate

Cantonment Public School and College, Rangpur

2010 - 2012 Secondary School Certificate

Cantonment Public School and College, Rangpur

CERTIFICATION

2017 Web Designer

BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM)

2017 Web Developer

Creative IT Institute

SKILLS



EXPERIENCE

2019 - 2021 Web Developer

Trimetric | Architects & Engineers

Indecor BD (Ecommerce)

www.indecor.com.bd

- Backend Development dynamic ecommerce (Furniture Shop) website
- Site integrated with SSLCommerce Payment and Messaging API
- Lookup hosting issues, client and staff logins and general upgrades/maintenance of servers

Satez Super Shop (Ecommerce)

www.satez.com.bd

- Woo commerce Based Grocery Ecommerce Website
- Integrated Cloud CDN and maintain Cloud server (Digital Ocean) issues

MIS (Management Information System)

- Develop internal MIS for company Project Management & HRM
- Backend Development using REST APIs built in Laravel PHP

2020 - Running UI - UX Design

Fiverr

Design web & mobile user interface at fiverr and other marketplace.

2018 - 2019 Web Developer & Digital Marketing Media Manager

Artact BD

- Develop websites from front to backend using PHP, JavaScript and HTML
- Designed and maintained both corporate and client websites
- Maintain Social Media Platform
- Design, delivering innovative concepts, wireframes & prototypes

EXPERTISE

